William Temple Franklin Papers 1775-1819 Mss.B.F86
American Philosophical Society
- William Temple Franklin Papers, 1775-1790; Mss.B.F86; 4.5 lin. feet
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 Janaury 8; ALS, 1p.; Schaffer, John
    Expressing gratitude for the services of Dr. Franklin in his behalf.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 Janaury 15; ALS, 2p.; Littlepage, Lewis
    Request for assistance in temporary financial embarrassment.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 January 16; ALS, 1p.; Arnoux, Abbè
    Declining an invitation to tea.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 January 20; ALS, 2p.; Grand, Henry
    Price of mourning buckles, etc.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 January 24; N. in 3d P. 1p.; de Diesbach, Comte
    Thanking him for a copy of the "Constitutions of the United States of America"; will call to see him with Chevalier Duplessis de Mauduit.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 January 24; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; de Salm Kyrbourg, Le Prince
    Apologizing for a misunderstanding.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 January 24; ALS, 1p.; Loiselle, L
    Asking for part payment for carriage.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 January 29; ALS, 1p.; Bache, Richard
    A request to forward letter.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 January 31; ALS, 2p.; Kéralio, Agathon Guynement, chevalier de
    Request to forward a packet. Gossip on Royal affairs.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 February 4; ALS, 1p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Request to have Dr. Franklin certify to the genuineness of letters of M. Golker.
  - to William Temple Franklin, [ca.1784] February 7; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Foulke, Dr. John
    Invitation for Monday evening.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 February 10; ALS, 2p.; Jeannotas, -----
    Requesting Franklin to recommend his hotel to friends in Philadelphia.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 February 15; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Vanderhorst, -----
    Acknowledging receipt of his billet, etc.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 February 19; ALS, 2p.; de Mirabeau, Comte
    Concerning a suitable English publisher for one of his books.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 February 24; ALS, 2p.; V. and P. French and Nephew
    Acknowledges receipt of payment of account. Inquires if Bayonne is to be a free port for Americans.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 February 27; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Concerning an "L. S." and an "S. C." which he has promised to procure for him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 February 29; ALS, 2p.; Woolford, Mrs. D. England
    Containing news of friends and acquaintances.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 March 6; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Requesting the return of his papers.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1784 March 7; ALS, 2p.; Bache, Richard
    Acknowledges receipt of power of attorney. Other personal items.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1784 March 28; ALS, 1p.; Beaumont, Jean-Baptiste-Jacques Elie de
    Begging Franklin's intervention with the Marquis Lafayette in behalf of Mr. [John] Schaffer.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1784 April 2; ALS, 3p.; Grand, Henry. England
    Regarding a coat a pins which have been delayed. Discusses contest between [Charles James] Fox, [Sir] Cecil Wray and Lord [Samuel] Hood.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1784 April 13; ALS, 3p.; Drummond, James
    Acknowledges courtesies shown his friend Mr. Ewart; writes in behalf of latter, regarding the Consulship at Barcelona, etc.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1784 April 13; ALS, 1p.; Sir Robert Herries and Co
    Acknowledge remittance from Robert Morris for copying machine for Mr. [Thomas] Jefferson.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1784 April 14; ALS, 1p.; Rayneval, Joseph Gérard de
    Sending a card requested by Mr. [John] Jay.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1784 April 15; ALS, 1p.; Carmichael, William, d. 1795
    A request to forward a letter to [Joseph Matthias Gérard] de Rayneval.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1784 April 17; ALS, 1p.; Hyde, Thomas
    Changing the date for a dinner engagement.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1784 ca.April.; ALS, 2p.; Grand, Henry. Bath
    With reference to a great coat and six (scarf) pins he is sending him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 May 5; N. in 3d P. 2p.; de Diesbach, Comte
    Expressing his regrets that he is obliged to leave immediately for Switzerland, owing to the serious state of his health, without being able to call on him. Will always treasure the book of the "Constitutions" as a souvenir from a descendant of the great Benjamin Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 May 14; ALS, 2p.; de Loutherbourg, La Baronne
    Requesting a letter of recommendation for a friend.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 May 21; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Hartley, -----
    Requesting a letter of introduction to some gentlemen at St. Cloud; and the loan of some pamphlets on the Aerostatic Globe.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 May 26; L.S. 2p.; Le Baron, -------
    Encloses a memoir of his claim against Capt. Mainvielle, of Charlestown, South Carolina, with request that it be laid before the authorities of that State.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 May 27; ALS, 2p.; Feriet, ---- baron de
    Asking a word of approval, to accompany some wine to be sent to Mr. [Richard] Bache.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 May 31; ALS, 1p.; Barclay, Thomas
    Concerning the functions of a Consul.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 May 31; ALS, 1p.; Jones, Capt. John Paul
    Thinks it would be more consistent for him not to appear at Court, when the Act of Congress is presented authorizing him to accept the Order of Military Merit.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 June 3; ALS, 1p.; Simonet, -----
    Discontinues lessons an account of ill-health.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 June 4; ALS, 1p.; Latouche, -----
    Requesting an order to have a piece of goods delivered to him for Madame [Le Ray] de Chaumont.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 June 13; ALS, 2p.; Barclay, Thomas
    Concerning [Le Ray] de Chaumont's accounts.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 June 16; ALS, 4p.; Fox, George
    Writes to him of Dr. [Edward] Bancroft; the marriage of [François] Barbé de Marbois; the adventures of "Chevalier de Longchamps."
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 June 17; ALS, 1p.; Le Mire, Noël
    Presenting a portrait of Le Marquis Lafayette.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 June 21; ALS, 3p.; Bache, Sarah
    Letter about various members of the family.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 June 21; ALS, 1p.; Bache, Richard
    Has forwarded the letter to John Holker.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 June 21; ALS, 2p.; ----- Revière, Chargé des Affaires of Saxony
    Request to forward a letter to Philadelphia.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 June 22; ALS, 2p.; Grand, Henry
    Suggests remedy for rash; gives commission to purchase handkerchiefs, etc.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 June 27; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Asks to have his accounts, as settled, deposited in the Consul's office for public inspection.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 June 28; L.S. 2p.; Le Maire de Gimel, Jacques
    Request to have his papers certified by Dr. Franklin, so that he may present them to Marquis de Castries.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 June 30; ALS, 3p.; Whitefoord, Caleb
    Gov. [William] Franklin has been in Sussex for the benefit of the seabathing; now back in London; at one time he had an intention of visiting Passy. Some time ago Mr. [Benjamin] West, having the opportunity of seeing three of the American Plenipo [tentiarie]s here and wishing to transmit their portraits to posterity in some historical picture, made a sketch of the signing of the Preliminary Treaty, to which he contributed by lending his portrait of Dr. Franklin by [Joseph] Wright, which be brought with him from Paris. There is only wanting (to make it complete) a head of the Secretary to the American Commission, which Mr. West requests you will send us. He has promised the portrait of Dr. Franklin, when Mr. West can spare it, to Mrs. [William] Hewson who, from her long acquaintance and great veneration for him, he thought highly deserving of such a present. He reserves a copy of it for himself and has given one to Mr. [William] Strahan.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 1; N. 1p.; de l'Harmonie, La Société
    An invitation to a meeting. Printed.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784] July 7; ALS, 2p.; Alexander, Miss Bethia.
    Going to dine with Mme. Helvétius on Wednesday. Will see him at Passy if he does not leave before then. Requests him to loan her his carriage horses.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 8; ALS, 1p.; Graff P. B
    Inquiring where a "perfect drawing of the American Order of Cincinnatus" can be obtained.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 10; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Graff P. B. St. Sauveur
    Acknowledges, with thanks, the information regarding the Order of Cincinnatus.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 10; L.S. 1p.; Skinner and Fenwick
    Regarding letters sent in their care for Mr. Sumners.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 31; ALS, 1p.; Bastard, Femme
    Concerning the purchase of a coat.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 13 and July 29; L.S. 3p. and 2p.; Grubb, J
    Soliciting aid in obtaining a Royal permit to marry a Catholic.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 16; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Enclosing bills for examination.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 17; ALS, 3p.; Cadet, -----
    Encloses a letter from Abbé Belin and recommends him as a teacher of French, Italian, Latin, etc.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 22; ALS, 1p.; Hayes, W
    Sends letters to be forwarded to friends in North Carolina.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 23; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Inquiring about an "affair" at the Palais Royal in which Mr. [David Salisbury] Franks was concerned.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 24; ALS, 1p.; de Stark, Capt
    Recalls their acquaintance at Lady Nicolson's. Wishes to have an interview with him about a prelate who desires to go to America to be of service to the Catholics in that country.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 26; ALS, 3p.; Elphinston, James
    Giving an account of books he has written, etc. Inquires about an English professorship in Paris.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 27; ALS, 1p.; Grand Painé,------
    Recommending a servant.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 July 31; Printed L.S. 1p.; Sir Robert Herries and Co
    A business announcement.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 August 1.; ALS, 2p.; Ridley, Matthew
    Request him to get an order form the Minister to let his baggage and furniture pass, which he is shipping to England and America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, [ca.1784] August 4; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; The Bishop of Derry
    Thanks him for getting him the lodgings.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 August 4; ALS, 3p.; Barclay, John
    Concerning the attachments at Nantes and l'Orient. The last letter he delivered to M. de Vergennes from Dr. Franklin was so clear, he thought the affair would end in a few days. Sent to the Marèchal de Castries the papers he wished to see relative to the seizure at
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 August 4.; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Bruet, -----, comte de
    Announcing the birth of a son.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 August 4; ALS, 2p.; Jones, D
    Request to discharge his account.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 August 6.; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Graff, P.B
    Sends him lace ruffles.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 August 10.; ALS, 2p.; Dumas, C.G.F.
    Refers to Dr. Franklin's malady [stone in the bladder]. Recommends a litter drawn by two mules, as the best conveyance in his case. Tells of Mr. [John] Adams's departure and his intention to rejoin Dr. Franklin and Mr. [Thomas] Jefferson at Paris.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 August 12; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Fitzmaurice, Lord
  - to William Temple Franklin, [1784] August 13; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Walterstorff, ----- de
    Requesting him to take charge of two letters for delivery on his arrival in London.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 August 18; ALS, 1p.; Jefferson, Thomas. [Paris.]
    Understands French imperfectly; asks him to fix his servants' compensation.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 August 19; ALS, 3p.; Grand, Henry. Manchester
    Giving information regarding London-lodgings, tradesmen, places of interest, etc.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784] August 20; N. in 3d P. 1p.; The Ambassador of Sweden. [Paris.]
    Enclosing a letter for Baron de Nolken.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 August 30; ALS, 3p.; de Lamotte, Lair
    Items of news about Dr. Franklin's and [Louis Guillaume] Le Veillard's health. Comments on the report of the Commissioners on Mesmerism. Mesmer not apparently affected by it.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 1; ALS, 1p.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin
    Tells of having gone to see his injured horse; dined at Mr. [Thomas] Barclay's.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1784 September 1; ALS, 1p.; Vaughan, Benjamin
    Invitation to stay at his house while in London.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 3; ALS, 2p.; Gimat, -----. Port Royal
    Acknowledging the introduction of M. de Jauge.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 5; ALS, 4p.; de Lamotte, Lair
    Refers to Mesmer's petition for a new commission to examine his discoveries.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 6; ALS, 3p.; Vaughan, Benjamin
    Arranging for visits and sight-seeing.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 7; ALS, 3p.; Le Veillard fils, Louis
    His opinion of [Mlle.] B[rillion]'s change of manner towards William Temple Franklin; comments on the new employment proposed to the latter. Tells of his love affairs.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 7; ALS, 1p.; Loiselle, L
    Regarding repairs to his carriage.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 9; ALS, 1p.; Vaughan, Benjamin
    List of new books on political matters.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 9; ALS, 2p.; Vaughan, Benjamin
    Invitation to dinnner.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 15; ALS, 1p.; Hutton, James
    Would have him meet Mrs. Dorothy Blunt and Mrs. [Mary] Hewson.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 15; ALS, 3p.; de Lamotte, Lair
    Tells of Dr. Franklin's health and of his having dined on two occasions at Auteuil. Refers to proposed ascent of the Robert's balloon. A new commission appointed to investigate Mesmer's theories. Arrival of John Jay and [Henry] Laurens in America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 16; ALS, 2p.; Littlepage, Lewis. Bialystok
    Asks for news of Marquis Lafayette; requests letters to be forwarded, etc.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 20; ALS, 1p.; de Fontenet, -----
    Making an appointment to introduce his nephew.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 20; ALS, 3p.; Le Veillard, Louis Guillaume
    Tells of [Comte de] Mirabeau being in London, after having lost the lawsuit with his wife; of the return of the Brillon family. The Dauphin has left Passy, much benefited by the new springs there. Describes the ascent of the Mm. Robert in the Duke of Chartres's baloon. M. and Mme. Caillot are leaving Passy to live at St. Germain.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 21; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Hesse, Mrs. Paddington
    Invitation to the play.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 22; ALS, 3p.; de Lamotte, Lair
    Mme. [Mariamne] Williams and other members of her family are staying with Dr. Franklin. Tells of reports about the Robert's balloon. M. [Louis Guillaume] Le Veillard still ill.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 23; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Gov William. Seaford
    Making an appointment to go with him to Windsor.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 September 25; A.N. in 3d P. 1p.; Price, Dr. Richard.
    An invitation to tea for himself and [Comte de] Mirabeau.
  - to William Temple Franklin, [1784] September 30; ALS, 2p.; Shipley, Jonathan, Bishop of St. Asaph. Chilbolton
    Invites William Temple Franklin to spend a few days in the country as he cannot go to London.
  - to William Temple Franklin, [1784?] October 1; ALS, 4p.; Grand, Henry. Brighthelmston
    Telling of his trip through Holland and from there to England; is delighted with everything he has seen in England. Will endeavor to get introduced to Governor William Franklin on his return to London.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 October 2; ALS, 1p.; Carrol, Archibald. Havre-de-Grace
    His ship, "Marianne," will sail for Norfolk, Virginia, in about ten days. Will be pleased to execute any commands that he may give.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 October 3; ALS, 2p.; de Lamotte, Lair
    Tells of the visit of Prince Henry [of Prussia], accompained by Marèchal de Biron, to Dr. Franklin. Refers to Abbè Morellet's trip to London with Lord Fitzmaurice.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 October 6; ALS, 4p.; de Lamotte, Lair
    Informs him that the portraits were sent to him by Abbè Morellet.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 October 11; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Price, Dr. Richard.
    Sends a pamphlet. Regrets his inability, owing to Mrs. Price's illness, to show him attention while in London, etc.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 October 12; ALS, 1p.; Vaughan, Benjamin
    Introducing Mr. [William] Godwin, who wishes information on Animal Magnetism, as he is translating the Commissioners' Report. Arranges for visits to various houses in London.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 October 13; ALS, 2p.; Shipley, Jonathan, Bishop of St. Asaph. Chilbolton
    Regrets not having seen [William Temple] Franklin at his house. Suggests the purchase of the account of the Dean of St. Asaph's Trial for Dr. Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 October 20; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Ordering the purchase of a bound edition of Tristram Shandy. An epigram in French on Animal Magnetism sent to Dr. Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 October 21; ALS, 2p.; de Lamotte, Lair
    Tells of the purchase of the St. Cloud property by the Queen; an immense balloon has been made in which the public will be allowed to go up on paying a fee. The Mesmer affairs dying out.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 October 23; ALS, 1p.; Wallace, John
    Has procured a Newfoundland pup. Awaits his orders.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 October 25; ALS, 1p.; Vaughan, Benjamin
    Gives addresses where cast iron coverings, pistols, etc., can be had. Declined invitation to Bowood and Chilbolton.
  - to William Temple Franklin, [1784] October 26; L. in 3d P. 2p.; Whatley, George
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 October 26; ALS, 1p.; Hewson, Mary Stevenson
    Hopes to see him at her house. Requests that he take for her a parcel of books for B[enjamin] F[ranklin] Bache.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 October 28; ALS, 1p.; Shipley, Jonathan
    Gladto hear of the prolongation of his visit. Hopes to see him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 October 30 and December 9; L.S. 2p and 3p.; Morris, Robert
    Regarding the payment of a claim made by William Temple Franklin and the investment of the same in shares of the Bank.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 1; ALS, 2p.; H-----, F-----.
    Rumors of Dr. Franklin's recall. Advises William Temple Franklin to make friends for himself. Warns him that the persons he sees most of are his enemies. Marquis Lafayette's exertions in behalf of Dr. Franklin are injurious to the latter.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 2; ALS, 1p.; Franks, David
    Introducing Madame de Villeneuve.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 2; ALS, 2p.; Morellet, Abbé. Bowood
    Has not heard from his parents or Mme. Helvètius since his arrival. Lord Fitzmaurice regrets William Temple Franklin cannot go to Bowood. Encloses some letters for friends in Paris.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 3; L. in 3d P.; Walter, John
    Asks for an appointment.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 3; ALS, 1p.; Hewson, Mary Stevenson. Cheam
    Is waiting to hear the date of his departure from London; wishes to go with him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 6; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Shipley, Georgiana. Chilbolton
    Pleasure derived from his short visit at Chilbolton; wishes to have it repeated.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 8; L. in 3d P. 1p.; de Magellan, Jean Hyacinthe
    Sends pamphlets which he requests him to deliver in Paris.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 9; ALS, 1p.; Caslon, William
    Sends cards of admission to Guildhall; advises full dress for the occasion.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 11; ALS, 3p.; Grand, Henry
    Commission to buy dress coat, buckles, etc.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 15; ALS, 1p.; Walter, John
    Sends two copies of "Letter A in English, French and Latin" one for Benjamin Franklin and one for Count d'Adhemar.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 16; ALS, 1p.; Whatley, George
    Sends a model of his "phiz" for Dr. Franklin; thinks it will travel safely. Hopes to receive one of the latter in return.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 18; ALS, 1p.; Hewson, Mrs Mary. Cheam
    Arranges for a visit from him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 19; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820
    Request to deliver a parcel to Dr. Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 21; ALS, 1p.; Vaughan, Benjamin
    Encloses a letter for Dr. Franklin. Asks for the loan of [Jacques] Turgot's "National Riches." Money matters.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784. November 22.; ALS, 3p.; Hewson, Mrs Mary. Cheam
    Tells him how to reach them; asks him to bring Mrs. Barbauld's "Lessons for Children" and "Sanford and Merton."
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 23; ALS, 1p.; Caslon, William
    Sends money due. Hopes horse will prove satisfactory.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 23; ALS, 1p.; Sir Robert Herries and Co
    Enclosing account of payments, etc.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 24; ALS, 2p.; Hewson, Mrs Mary. Rochester
    This comes of his not keeping his appointment. Writes by same post to Dover to learn of his whereabouts.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 25; ALS, 2p.; Hill, James
    Prices of locket for Comte d'Artois, and other purchases.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 26; Printed N. in 3d P. 1p.; Paris, -----
    Announcing the birth of a daughter.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 November 26; ALS, 1p.; Geyer, Frederick William
    Enclosing a letter for Mr. Nath[anie]l Tracy. Dr.[John] Jeffries ascends with M. [François] Blanchard next week.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 December 7; ALS, 1p.; Luton, William. Abbeville
    Has been detained by bad weather. Hopes to bring the horse and dog safely to Passy within a week.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 December 11; ALS, 2p.; Grand, Henry. Bath
    Acknowledges receipt of waistcoats. Inquires about dress coat, etc. Beauties of Bath.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 December 13; L.S. 2p.; Houdetot, Comtesse d'
    Requests the loan of a book by Mr. [Richard] Price on the "Constitution of the United States" in which is to be found a letter, in French, by [Jacques] Turgot.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1784 December 14; ALS, 3p.; Bache, Richard